# JACK MAHONEY

## CHICAGO, IL

Phone Number: 517-574-8060 Email: mahonej79@gmail.com LinkedIn: Jack's Profile GitHub: Jack's GitHub

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Jack is a software engineer with full stack development experience and a background in cybersecurity and electrical engineering. He has experience in infrastructure support and collaborating with diverse technical teams, specializing in optimizing end-user experiences. Jack's technical proficiency covers various technologies, with a particular expertise in building user-friendly web applications and managing large amounts of data.

#### **SKILLS**

## **Software Engineering Skills:**

- Front-End: JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML, React, Redux
- Data: SQL, PostgreSQL
- Back-End: Go, Node.JS, C
- Tooling: Visual Studio Code, Git, Azure DevOps, JIRA, ServiceNow, Amazon AWS, Azure Cloud, Docker

### Additional Technical Skills:

- Network technologies, protocols, ports, API management, and network segmentation strategies
- Server and end-user device security, including patch management
- Disaster recovery planning, testing, and fault tolerance strategies
- Cybersecurity principles, best practices, and industry standards such as NIST and ISO

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Cybersecurity Engineer and Risk Management Lead, Infrastructure - Northern Trust - Chicago IL August 2022 - Present

- Utilized familiarity with various programming languages and database technologies, to conduct comprehensive evaluations of the infrastructure team's technology components, as well as application development practices. Identified and prioritized potential risks and vulnerabilities, proposing effective mitigation strategies to protect critical assets and data. Initiatives led to effective responses of 100+ acknowledged information requests from regulators during horizontal exam
- Leveraged knowledge of cybersecurity principles and experience to work with application teams, providing directions for integration of robust security controls into both infrastructure and SDLC processes. Responsible for implementation and development of effective controls that led to reduced infrastructure organizational risk ratings

## Cybersecurity Senior Consultant - Optiv Security - Chicago, IL

July 2021 - August 2022

 Maximized cybersecurity maturity and IT asset value by helping clients understand business sectors for improvement based on NIST and ISO 27001 standards, licensing rules that create compliance risk, unnecessary spending, top cyber threats to the network (internal and external), securing the Software and Development Lifecycle (SDLC), and how the IT Asset Lifecycle fits into each organization's cybersecurity practice

# Cyber Risk Consultant & Senior Consultant - Deloitte - Chicago, IL

January 2019 - July 2021

 Served multiple Fortune 500 clients, as well as other clients in a diverse array of industries, including the Financial Sector, Semiconductors & Electrical Components, Healthcare, Athletic Apparel, and the Education Sector on how to reduce overall cyber risk by leveraging industry leading practices for Asset Management at the foundational level

#### **Software Projects**

- Built and deployed <u>jack-mahoney.com</u> website using modern front-end technologies such as JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, React, HTML, front-end components, and APIs to showcase proficiency in creating visually appealing and user-friendly interfaces
- Built a <u>JSON API project</u> with JSON Web Token authentication, PostgreSQL integration, and Docker deployment. Project simulates building of a bank API from scratch, with optimized performance by utilizing only essential packages.
  Demonstrated commitment to quality with the implementation of thorough testing for each HTTP handler to ensure a reliable and secure system

#### **EDUCATION**